## **NISHAT ANJUM**

□+8801723124778 | Image: Imag

## Summary\_

Senior Software Engineer with a decade of impressive background in designing and developing enterprise-level software solutions. My expertise lies in JAVA and JVM-based technology stacks, software design patterns, and development methodologies. After scrutinizing my passion, comprehensive work experience, and definitive ambition, I have decided to pursue a research route Master's Program in my field of interest, which I believe will lead me to a career as a Computer and Information Specialist in the future.

Education 2.

University of Dhaka Dhaka, Bangladesh

BSc. (Honours) in Computer Science and Engineering

2007 - 2011

- CGPA: 3.37/4.00 (3.40 in last 2 academic years)
- Merit Position: 14th out of 45 students
- Courses: Software Engineering, Database Management System, Operating System, Computer Networks, Data Communication, Data Structures, Algorithms, Discrete Mathematics, Theory of Computation, Database, Artificial Intelligence
- **IELTS**: Overall Band Score **7.5** [L-9, R-7.5, W-7, S-6.5]

## Research Interests

Software Engineering, Empirical Software Engineering, Application of Machine Learning in Software Engineering, Database and knowledge-base systems, Data Mining, Data Visualization, Human Computer Interaction.

## Academic Research\_

### Title: Throughput Maximization in Device to Device(D2D) Enabled Cellular Network

University Of Dhaka

Supervisor: Professor DR. MD. ABDUR RAZZAQUE

2012

In this work, We addressed the spectrum-sharing problem between cellular and underlaying D2D communication. Our main goal was
to maximize the throughput of the underlying 3G cellular network in non-orthogonal Resource-Sharing mode. We proposed a Scheduled
resource-sharing Algorithm for eNodeB that intelligently identified potential D2D connection pairs and optimally shared UpLink and DownLink resources. The algorithm calculated The SINR of each cellular and probable D2D pairs and selected the resource with optimal SINR for
sharing with D2D pair.

## Technical Expertise

**Language:** Java, Python, C/C++, JavaScript, TypeScript, R

Frameworks: Spring-(Boot, Security, MVC, Webflow, Data JPA, Batch, Hateoas, GraphQL), Python Flask, Angular, Hibernate, JPA, Mockito

Web Services: REST, SOAP

**Middlewares:** WebLogic, WildFly, Tomcat, TomcatEE, Glassfish

**Databases:** MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, In-memory Data Structure Store-REDIS, Cloud Object Storage - MINIO

**Tools:** Maven, Gradle, Ant, Postman, Git, Bitbucket, Docker

**OS Platforms:** Linux, Windows, Mac

Big Data: Kafka, Apache KUDU, Apache Spark, Apache Druid, Elasticsearch

## Work Experience\_\_\_\_

### TigerIT Bangladesh Limited. 🗹

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Senior Software Engineer

Oct 2019 - present

- Supervising a team of four software engineers to ascertain the successful completion of deliverables of four country-scale projects.
- Perform various RnD and provide expert support and guidance on architectural changes in ongoing initiatives taken by the company.
- Continuously contribute to troubleshooting issues in production deployment and performance tuning.
- Review code for defects and quality against technical documents and standard practices.

Software Engineer

Jan 2016 - Sept 2019

- Extensively re-engineered legacy software system to improve scalability and increased performance by approximately 35%.
- Core architect of a large-scale data migration project involving a highly complex process that successfully migrated approximately 120M
   Demographic and Biometric data within 42 hours.
- Developed High volume and low latency Restful APIs for various client applications serving responses less than 30ms.
- Developed data streaming pipeline using Apache Kafka that combine messaging and storage of both historical and real-time data.
- Developed a high-performance real-time fast data Analytics application using Apache Druid, Kudu, and Kafka.
- Designed and developed Report modules for multiple ongoing projects which involved complex query writing.
- · Assisted the Junior Software Engineers in solving technical problems and mentored them in writing high-quality code.

Oct 2014 - Dec 2015

Jan 2013 - Sept 2014

**Associate Software Engineer** 

- Worked with Technical Staff to understand problems with software and correct them.
- Developed new features for the MAR module of The Therap application.
- Wrote a successful migration script incorporating ETL process to store lookup standard diagnosis codes (e.g. ICD-9/10).
- Solved user reported bugs of different modules in the Therap Application.
- Learning and experimenting the usability of various technologies in The Therap application.

Junior Software Engineer

- · Learning, installing and reviewing various technologies related to software development.
- Investigated users reported bugs in the codebase and resolved them.
- Did code refactoring to increase readability and performance in different modules.

# Industrial Projects 🗹

#### **Bangladesh NID application System**

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring MVC, Spring Security, JSP, Semactic-UI, JQuery]

• An online public portal where citizen of Bangladesh can apply for NID card and voter registration

### Rohingya AFIS And AFRS adjudication System

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Python Flusk, Angular.js, Spring Boot, Ouartz Scheduler]

An application which ceaselessly verifies new voter applications with Rohingya AFIS and AFRS database

#### **CMS system for Election Commission Officials**

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring Boot, Spring Security, JWT Token, JSP, Bootstrap, vue.js]

· Web Application for bangladesh election commission officials to oversee voter registration and NID card applications

#### **Bangladesh Citizen data Migration Project**

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring Boot-Scheduling, JDBC, Apache Kafka, Redis]

 A data migration project to migration 120M voter demographic and biometric data to elasticsearch, Apache KUDU, Redis, Minio and Oracle database.

### **Nepal HSENP Registration System**

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring MVC, Spring Security, JSP, Semactic UI, JQuery]

· A online public portal where Nepal Citizen can apply for high security embossed number plate for their Vehicles.

### **Nepal HSENP Application management System**

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring MVC, Spring Security, Thymeleaf, Bootstrap, JQuery, Oracle database]

• A web application for nepal DOTM officials to supervise HSENP printing applications.

#### Nepal vehicle data migration project

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring-Batch, Spring-Jdbc, Oracle Database]

A data migration projects to migrate 35M vehicle data to Oracle database.

#### **Bangladesh NTMC National Datahub Project**

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring Boot, Spring Security, JWT Token, Apache Kafka, Redis, GraphQL]

· An ETL project for bangladesh NTMC which accumulate Citizen data from multiple sources and make them accessible for

## **Vehicle Tracking System - Banngladesh NTMC**

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Alient JAVA SDK, MQTT, Caffeine Cache, Spring Boot, Spring Scheduling]

The application unceasingly accumulates vehicle movement information by interfacing with Alien RFID Reader

# Therap Application

Therap BD Ltd.

Technology Stack: [Spring MVC, JSP, EJB, Hibernate JPA, Oracle Database]

- Developed new feature in Medication Administration Record (MAR) module to record patient medication record
- Developed a migration project to store lookup standard ICD-9/10 diagnosis code into relational Database

# **Academic Projects**

## Buddy Circle-A Social networking web application 🗹

University Of Dhaka

**Internet Programming** 

2012

• An application developed back in 2012 using spring mvc, jsp, html5, jpa, mysql

### Tic Tac Toe Game using ATmega32 microcontroller

University Of Dhaka

Computer Peripherals and Interfacing

2010

2010

• A multiplayer tic-tac-toe game written in C language for ATmega32 Controller

#### **Dots and Boxes - Online Multiplayer Game**

University Of Dhaka

Object Oriented Programming-JAVA

An online multiplayer game developed using JAVA Applet and socket programming

University Of Dhaka

Programming Language Fundamental- C Language

2008

• A simple single player game developed using C i-Graphics library

University Of Dhaka

Unix Shell

**Avoid collision Game** 

2009

A simple bash like Unix shell which executed linux command using exec().